(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Are you ready?
Let's have a game!
La la la...
Ooh!
Ugh...
Yeah, let's go!
Hahahaha!
Huh?
Hah! Hah!
Mmm...
What the?!
Ah! Ah!
Ahhhhh!
Ah!
Oww... Ugh...
Ah... Ah...
Dang it!
Ugh...
Ah...
Uh, what's going on?
Where... Where am I?
Eh?
No way!
Did I get sucked into the game world?
Woah... Wha...
What do I do?
Hello?
Oh.
Why are there so many eyes on me?
H-Hello?
Hello?
They're not saying anything.
Oh...
I have to get back.
Today is such an important day,
I can't get stuck in here!
Ugh, what should I do?
I guess I have to... figure this out on my own. Um...
Well...
There's so many people looking at me.
Are those Pebbles? Hello?
Are you expecting me to do something?
Maybe I should... sing and dance?
'Cause this looks like a stage.
Maybe...
Okay, I got it then.
I'm gonna sing and dance a song right now!
Here we go!
This Game!
回り続ける 歯車には成り下がらない
I will never degenerate into a continuously turning gear.
平均演じる 誕生から始まった地獄
Playing the average, a hell that started from birth.
遊び半分で 神が導いた 盤上の世界
The board world that God led with half-playfulness.
No no no game no life
ぬるい平穏を ばっさり切り捨てて
Cut away the lukewarm peace entirely,
栄光の階段に 存在刻むんだ
And carve your existence into the stairs of glory.
目に映るのは 完全勝利の運命
What is reflected in my eyes is the fate of complete victory.
何もかも 計算通り
Everything is according to plan.
変えてやる 染まらない空白で
I'll change it with an undyed blank.
We are Maverick 救済なんていらない
We are Maverick, we don't need salvation.
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what unreasonableness attacks,
勝てばいいだけの 話だろう
It's just a matter of winning, isn't it?
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite invincibility.
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
I'll enjoy it with this reborn life.
自分だけは自分 信じてる
Only I believe in myself.
心に潜む 闇より強い相手はいない
There is no opponent stronger than the darkness lurking in the heart.
挫ける限り そこに敗北はありえない
As long as you don't give up, there is no defeat.
上辺の個性で 安心と引き換えに
Don't exchange your peace of mind for superficial individuality...
プライド殺すな
...and kill your pride.
No no no sense of life
野蛮な雑音を キッパリ蹴飛ばして
Kick away the savage noise decisively,
誰より純粋な 声上げるんだ
And raise a voice purer than anyone else's.
戦うことは きっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is definitely not a mistake.
手応えが 教えてくれた
The response taught me that.
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if you lose everything, survive and win.
We are Maverick 常識なんていらない
We are Maverick, we don't need common sense.
前へならえ 向かう先に
Align to the front; ahead of where we're heading...
待ってるのは退屈だろう
...only boredom is waiting.
言いなりじゃ つまらない
It's boring to just do as you're told.
挑んでやる
I'll challenge it.
生まれ直した命も 駒にして
Using even this reborn life as a game piece,
自分だけの道を 最後まで
I'll follow my own path to the very end.
迷わない 選ばれし者
I won't hesitate, as the chosen one.
真っ赤な自惚れでも
Even if it's sheer conceit,
誇らしく 生き抜くための
Because I only know one way...
方法を一つしか 知らないから
...to survive proudly.
We are Maverick 救済なんていらない
We are Maverick, we don't need salvation.
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what unreasonableness attacks,
勝てばいいだけの 話だろう
It's just a matter of winning, isn't it?
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite invincibility.
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
I'll enjoy it with this reborn life.
この世界 手にして 笑うんだ
I'll take this world in my hands and laugh.
We are Maverick 最強の Maverick Gamers
We are Maverick, the strongest Maverick Gamers.
空白ならば 何者にもなれる
If it is blank, I can become anything.
自分だけは自分
Only I...
信じてる
...believe in myself.
Yeah! How was that?
That was the best performance ever, right?
Hey, over there! You liked it, right?
Hey!
With this, I should be able to get back to my own world.
Alright everybody! Beam me up, Pebbles!
Ah! Uh! Ahhh!
Why is it shaking?!
Yeahhh!
No!
Where are you going?!
Dang it.
Well, according to video game logic...
...this must mean I must now go on an epic quest to find the coins or something.
But I don't have time for that!
I need the coins back to get home! No!
Huh?
Oh, what's this?
Uh, I mean, I came out through there, so...
Maybe this will take me, you know, on my next step of my quest?
Well, better than being stuck here. So...
Let's go!
Ahhh!
Huh? I'm not back in my world?
え？ここどこ？
Eh? Where am I?
(Evil Laugh)
待ってたよ、ビジュー。
I've been waiting for you, Bijou.
Robocosan Joins the Battle!
え？ロボ子さんパイ？
Eh? Robocosan-pai?
探しているのは... これ？
Is this... what you're looking for?
Ah! Coin! The Coin!
これがないと元の世界に戻れないんでしょ？
You can't return to your world without this, right?
でもそうはさせない。
But I won't let you.
ゲームマスターである僕たちから...
From us, the Game Masters...
全て取り戻せるかな？
...can you win everything back?
え？ほんと？帰れるの？あれ？え？あ？
Eh? Really? I can go home? Huh? Eh? Ah?
と、とにかく！このコインが欲しければ...
A-Anyway! If you want this coin...
僕と... 勝負だ！
...battle me!
A match?
そう！Yes！
Right! Yes!
格闘ゲームで... 勝負だ！
Battle... in a fighting game!
Mmm... Alright! I won't lose!
Nooooo!
L & R... UP & B... L R Dash...
& B... L R Dash & B...
L R STOP & TALK B B A B S(tart)
これが私をリモートコントロールする機械です
This is the machine that remote controls me.
少し歪な形しておりますが、使えます
It's a bit misshapen, but it is usable.
UP SIDE DOWN A B A B B A B A 左 右
UP SIDE DOWN A B A B B A B A Left Right
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK NO GLITCH
もうちょっとで外に出られるのにな
Even though I could go outside in just a little bit...
どうやってもうまくいかない
No matter what I do, it doesn't work.
まだまだ足りない
It's still not enough.
座る 座る (sit down please)
Sit, sit (sit down please)
フィードバック 体に混ぜて 廻る 廻る
Feedback, mixing in my body, spinning, spinning.
Turn it round
唸りを上げてモーター状態
The motor is roaring.
踊る 踊る (dancing night)
Dancing, dancing (dancing night)
マッシュアップで漏れなくアガル
Getting high flawlessly with a mashup.
声を上げて (singing now)
Raise your voice (singing now)
あの子よりもうまく歌いたい
I want to sing better than that girl.
これが僕をリモートで操縦できる機械です
This is the machine that can remote control me.
説明書は紛失しておりますが使えます
The manual is lost, but it is usable.
うなだれてるその顔を上げて
Lift up that hanging head of yours.
視点・視界・合わせて
Align your viewpoint and vision.
今日はかなり本気だぜ
I'm pretty serious today.
ほらすぐにキメるぜ
Come on, I'll decide it right now.
座る 座る (oh) SIT DOWN PLEASE
Sit down, sit down, (oh) SIT DOWN PLEASE
フィードバックに体預けて
Give your body to the feedback.
廻る 廻る (oh) TURN IT AROUND
Spin, spin, (oh) TURN IT AROUND
うなりをあげてモーター状態
The motor roars to life.
踊る 踊る (oh) DANCIN' NIGHT
Dance, dance, (oh) DANCIN' NIGHT
マッシュアップで群れなすビット
Bits swarming in a mashup.
声を 上げて (oh) SINGIN' NOW
Raise your voice, (oh) SINGIN' NOW
あの子みたいなヒトになりたい
I want to become a person like that girl.
惚れた腫れたの七色サムライ
A seven-colored samurai in love.
洗いざらい主張する存在
An existence asserting everything.
思い違いが透けてる塩梅
The misunderstanding is transparent.
怖いくらいのわくわく状態
A state of excitement that's almost scary.
気にしないのが貴方のポリシー
Not caring is your policy.
悩んでいてもお腹は減るし
Even if I'm worried, I still get hungry.
なんだかんだで世間はヘルシー
In one way or another, the world is healthy.
お気を確かにぬるま湯男子
Stay strong, lukewarm boy.
いぃぃぃぃ...
Eeeee...
うぉぉぉぉ...
Wooooo...
もうちょっとで隙間埋まるのに
Just a little more and the gap would be filled...
いいな いいな
That's nice, that's nice.
どうやっても上手くいかねぇ
No matter what I do, it doesn't go well.
あぁ もう時間が 足りない
Ah, I'm already running out of time.
座る 座る SIT DOWN PLEASE
Sit down, sit down, SIT DOWN PLEASE
フィードバックに体預けて
Give your body to the feedback.
廻る 廻る TURN IT AROUND
Spin, spin, TURN IT AROUND
うなりをあげてモーター状態
The motor roars to life.
踊る 踊る DANCIN' NIGHT
Dance, dance, DANCIN' NIGHT
マッシュアップで群れなすビット
Bits swarming in a mashup.
声を 上げて SINGIN' NOW
Raise your voice, SINGIN' NOW
あの子みたいなヒトになりたい
I want to become a person like that girl.
座る 座る SIT DOWN PLEASE
Sit down, sit down, SIT DOWN PLEASE
廻る 廻る TURN IT AROUND
Spin, spin, TURN IT AROUND
踊る 踊る DANCIN' NIGHT
Dance, dance, DANCIN' NIGHT
声を 上げて SINGIN' NOW
Raise your voice, SINGIN' NOW
あの子みたいなヒトになりたい
I want to become a person like that girl.
Wahoo! I win!
No...
Coin! Yay!
Yeah! I got a coin!
Whoa... Go to the next stage...
But... be careful...
次のゲームマスターは...
The next game master...
僕のようにはいかないぞ。
won't be like me.
No easy.
大丈夫だよ！
It'll be okay!
ビブーだから！
Because I'm Biboo!
Oh, okay.
ありがとう先輩！
Thank you, Senpai!
じゃあ、バイバイ！
Well then, bye bye!
Bye bye Biboo!
Congratulations!
Bye bye Roboco-san!
Uwaa! Ouch...
Where...
Now then...
Where to next I wonder...
We've been waiting for you, Biboo.
Wow.
Huh? IRyS? Ina?
Hmm. I'm assuming this...
...is what you're looking for, right?
Oh, why are you guys so cool? Yes, yes, I need that!
Give me, give me!
We won't just hand it over.
What?
You'll have to race for it.
Eh? Yes... No... Give it! Where are you putting that?
I'm putting that back in my pocket.
No! Where are you going? No!
If you want it, you have to beat us.
Are you ready to battle?
Fine! I'll be cool too. Watch this.
Okay... I won't lose!
GO ONE TWO GO ONE TWO GO MY SHINE TONIGHT
NO ONE CAN STOP MY SHINE TONIGHT
Save me, I think I'm freezing up so cold inside
With that quiet cool look, look at you
Save me, I need a guiding touch in these dark times
Boy be the catching machine
Inside the maze of your heart...
...I'm the soul that strays
Baby baby look at me, you're not blind
Oh can't you see that I can be refined
Your heart is super hot right now
It's time to be your Diamond Girlfriend
Overheating love machine burning hot hot hot hot
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me...
...let them light the way
Precious girlfriend, go go go!
Overheating love machine burning hot hot hot hot
I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all, break it all
The Diamond Girlfriend!
逆境なら上等
Bring on the adversity
ヒビと My Toy
Cracks and My Toy
撒き散らす Noise
Scattering Noise
Bling-bling no sparkles
Bling-bling sparkles
Just heat it and wheel it, make the soul a cherry
眩しさで目が眩むじゃん
It's so bright it's blinding
Trust me, your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
言葉なしで伝わる愛
Love conveyed without words
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
僕が照らしてあげる
I'll light the way for you
Under the pressure and fire...
...see these ashes reformed
Brand new show, you who I really am
In the name of love I'll be a gem
Your heart is super hot right now
It's time to be your Diamond Girlfriend
Overheating love machine burning hot hot hot hot
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
Precious girlfriend, go go go!
Overheating love machine burning hot hot hot hot
I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all, break it all
The Diamond Girlfriend!
Now see is your atomic symbol
グルグル回る真っ赤になるまで Limbo
Spinning round and round, limbo until it turns bright red
愛が足りないとか闇が深いほど
The more love is lacking, the deeper the darkness
価値が増す Gem let's go, I'm a jeweler
This Gem's value increases, let's go, I'm a jeweler
さあ、踊りなさい！
Now, dance!
Shine on, shine bright, light my flame
Until it all melts away
Are you ready?!
Overheating love machine burning hot hot hot hot
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
Precious girlfriend, go go go!
Overheating love machine burning hot hot hot hot
I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all, break it all
The Diamond Girlfriend!
No one can know, I shine tonight
No one can know, I shine!
やったー！
I did it!
Woohoo!
Are you guys okay?
大丈夫！ Yeah!
We're okay! Yeah!
大丈夫？
You okay?
やった！ I won!
Yay! I won!
Yeah! I got the coin!
I'm the winner! I win!
Oh? A portal?
By the way, where did the coin come from, IRyS?
It came from my Nephilim pocket.
Bye bye!
Oh, bye bye!
Ahhh! The world is spinning!
Ouch... ouch...
Dizzy...
Huh? Just a puzzle stage?
Hey! I'm ready for my next challenge now!
Hey come out!
Hey!
There's no... Game Master this time?
Eh?
Well, I guess I could use a break or something then.
Hmm, maybe I'll dance and sing by myself, you know, as a refresher.
Yes, I'll be ready for the next challenge.
This is a puzzle stage, so it does remind me of a certain song.
Hey! Everyone over there!
You want to hear it too, right?
Yeah?
Okay. They didn't say anything, I'm just talking to myself.
Well, alright then!
Let's dance!
Tetris!
どうして擦れてしまうの
Why do I wear away?
挺身で苦しんで呪縛塔
Suffering with devotion in the binding tower,
更新で振り向いて行きましょうか
Shall we turn around with an update?
悪くない
Not bad.
興味で即位派で感動
Moved by the enthronement faction out of interest,
情味で薬食べてバット
Eating medicine with sentiment, bad trip,
調理で振る舞ってみたって暗号化
Even if I try to serve it cooked, it's encrypted.
金による
It depends on money.
常識で狂い振る乱闘
A brawl driven mad by common sense,
欲して連印組んでバンド
Wanting it, forming a seal-alliance band,
祖信で苦しんでも完治問わず
Suffering from ancestral beliefs, regardless of a cure.
くたばえる
Drop dead.
どうして優れてしまうの
Why do you excel?
どうして救いてしまうの
Why do you save me?
どうしてそこ壊れちゃったかな
Why did it break right there?
パラパラパラ
Para para para.
近未来近かった
The near future was close,
ショッピングモール天才コンプ
Shopping mall genius completion,
ショーウィンドウ引っ掛かった
Got caught in the show window.
文字化るな景気リビンバル
Don't get garbled, economic living bar.
悪目立ち
Standing out in a bad way,
百歩譲る足音付き
Giving a hundred steps, with footsteps,
ユースを添えて
Add some youth.
テテテテテテトリス
Te-te-te-te-te-Tetris!
どうしてこんな目に
Why am I going through this?
興味がないこと本気じゃないもの
Things I'm not interested in, things I'm not serious about,
全部後回しで
Putting them all off for later.
知ってることは知らんぷり
Feigning ignorance about things I know,
私は終わってる
I'm hopeless.
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの
Those who know my embarrassing past,
記憶消し去って
Erase their memories.
迷惑かけてごめんてばね
I said I'm sorry for causing trouble,
誰か助けて
Someone help me.
盲信で直ぐ光っちゃうの
I shine immediately with blind faith,
虚心で直ぐ光っちゃうの
I shine immediately with an empty mind.
知りたくない 知りたくない 知りたくない
I don't want to know, I don't want to know, I don't want to know.
問診で直ぐ引っ掛かるさと
Getting caught immediately in the diagnosis,
貯金で軽い立つ窓
A window standing lightly on savings.
生きたくない 生きたくない 生きたくない Bye Bye
I don't want to live, I don't want to live, I don't want to live. Bye Bye.
緊急急行センターポール
Emergency express center pole,
ナイチンゲールな配信技
Nightingale-like streaming technique,
名刺交換の迷信
Superstition of exchanging business cards,
直近ボールで契るハイボール
Highball pledged with the latest ball.
お天旅行
A heavenly trip,
殺到良い箇所こじつけ
Forcing good points in a rush,
早く行け
Go quickly.
テテテテテテトリス
Te-te-te-te-te-Tetris!
共感性羞恥
Vicarious embarrassment.
あーとかそーとか忙しくて
Saying 'ah' and 'so', I'm too busy,
眠れないわ今日も
I can't sleep today either.
誰か早く殴ってきて
Someone come hit me quickly,
気絶させてくれよ
And knock me out.
人生キャンセル キャンセル界隈
Life cancel, cancel community,
ぼんやりとした不安
A vague anxiety.
私のせい 私が悪いの
It's my fault, I'm the bad one,
そうだよ
That's right.
興味が出ても本気でやっても
Even if I get interested, even if I try seriously,
全部空回りで
Everything spins out of control.
知らないくせに嘘つき
Lying even though you don't know,
私は終わってる
I'm hopeless.
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの
Those who know my embarrassing past,
記憶消し去って
Erase their memories.
迷惑かけてごめんてばね
I said I'm sorry for causing trouble,
誰か助けて
Someone help me.
迷惑かけてごめんてばね
I said I'm sorry for causing trouble,
誰か許して
Someone forgive me.
Well, that scared me.
I don't know, this game's bugged, man.
Hey, someone report these bugs! Dang it!
Cubes start popping out and everything starts...
Who designed this? I need to meet the devs!
Hey devs!
This game is malfunction[ing]... but
I don't have time for that.
I gotta find the coins.
Eh? Oh.
I guess that's my cue to leave.
Okay. Next stage!
Let's charge up!
Helicopter! Helicopter!
I gotta work on that landing.
Eh? Oh. Wow, what a cute stage!
Kawaii!
Oh? Oh?
どうもどうも、待ってましたよ、Biboo!
Welcome, welcome, I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Fubuki-senpai?!
Bibooは、これが欲しいんだよね？
Biboo, you want this, right?
Hi! 欲しい！欲しい！
Yes! I want it! I want it!
ならば、白上と勝負だ！
If so, then face Shirakami in a match!
白上のクレーンゲームから果たして逃げられるかな？
Can you really escape from Shirakami's crane game?
Eh? Mmm... Okay then!
負けないよ！
I won't lose!
LONELY ROLLING STAR
陽だまり
A patch of sunshine...
サンサン
...shining brightly.
心は
My heart is...
晴れ模様
...having sunny weather.
二つの
My two...
瞳は
...eyes are...
向日葵
...like sunflower...
の種なのよ
...seeds.
語らい
Talking,
重なり
overlapping,
固まり
clumping together,
絡まり
entangling.
一緒に
Being together...
いること
...is an...
絶対
...absolute...
必然
...necessity.
でもあなた大事な
But you paint...
夢を描く
...your precious dream.
終わるまでは
Until it ends...
ずっとそこで
...stay right there.
You're Lonely Rolling Star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't you stop now.
You're Lonely Rolling Star
さあ前を向いて行こう
Come on, let's face forward and go.
星空
The starry sky...
キラキラ
...is twinkling.
金平糖
It's like...
のようなの
...konpeito candy.
甘くて
Sweet...
切ない
...and heartrending.
思いが
My feelings...
募るの
...are growing stronger.
抱きしめた想いは
The feelings I embraced...
夜空を舞い
...dance in the night sky.
急降下して
Nosediving...
あなたの元へ
...straight to you.
届くかな
Will it reach you?
You're Lonely Rolling Star
ああ息切らさないでよね
Ah, don't run out of breath.
You're Lonely Rolling Star
たまには電話して
Call me once in a while.
You're Lonely Rolling Star
会いたい夜はすぐ
On nights I want to see you, come right away.
You're Lonely Rolling Star
ああ溜め息が一つ
Ah, a single sigh...
こぼれる
...spills out.
Lonely Rolling
退屈
Boredom,
待った
waited.
あの場所で
At that place,
待ち合わせしようか
shall we meet up?
You're Lonely Rolling Star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't you stop now.
You're Lonely Rolling Star
思い出してよね
Please remember me.
You're Lonely Rolling Star
待っていられない
I can't just wait.
もうね
Already...
夜の匂い
it's the scent of the night.
さあ
Come on...
前を向いて
look forward...
行こう
let's go!
Ah... Phew!
I think we're doing great now, aren't we?
Who's next, huh?
I'm ready for my next challenge.
Fwah fwah fwah!
待っていたぞ、Biboo。
I've been waiting, Biboo.
Hajime? Whaaaat?
これが欲しければ...
If you want this...
童と勝負だ。
you'll have to beat me.
My coin!
番長のダンスについてこれるかな？
Can you keep up with the Bancho's dance?
Eh? Dance?
Hmph. Okay.
Let's dance together!
Yeah! Yeah!
みんな！チルノの算数教室始まるよ！
Everyone! Cirno's math class is about to start!
あたいみたいな天才目指して頑張っていってね！
Work hard and aim to be a genius like me!
キラキラ ダイアモンド
Sparkling diamond,
輝く星のように
like a shining star.
栄光志望校
To the glorious school of my choice,
なんとかして入ろう
let's get in somehow.
天才！秀才！トップ目指して！
Genius! Prodigy! Aim for the top!
Go! Go!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
ちょっ！バカじゃないもん！
Hey! I'm not an idiot!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
バカって言うほうがバカなのよ！
The one who says 'idiot' is the idiot!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
なによ！うるさいわね！このバカ！
What! You're annoying! You idiot!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
てれん てれん てれん...
Teren teren teren...
紅魔館から
From the Scarlet Devil Mansion,
バスが出て
a bus departs.
はじめに三人乗りました
At first, three people boarded.
白玉楼で
At Hakugyokurou,
一人降りて
one person got off,
半人だけ乗りました
and only half a person boarded.
八雲さんちで
At the Yakumo house,
二人降りて
two people got off.
結局乗客合計何人だ？
In the end, how many passengers are there?
答えは答えはゼロ人ゼロ人
The answer is, the answer is, zero people!
なぜならなぜならそれは
Because, because that is...
幻想郷にバス無い
there are no buses in Gensokyo!
山落ち
The punchline...
意味など無いわ
has no meaning.
キャラクター立てばいいのよ
As long as the character stands out, it's fine!
元気があればなんでも
If you have energy, you can do anything!
1！2！9！
One! Two! Nine!
くるくる時計の針
Spinning, spinning clock hands.
ぐるぐる頭まわる
My head is spinning round and round.
だって
Because...
つぶら目玉
my round eyes,
二つしかないのに
I only have two of them,
三本の針なんて
so three hands on a clock...
ちんぷんかん
is total nonsense!
次々
One after another,
問題出る
problems appear.
まだまだ授業続く
The class still continues.
凍る
Freezing...
部屋の中
inside the room.
ひんやりした温度も
The chilly temperature,
時間も気にせず
ignore the time and...
ゆっくりしていってね！
take it easy!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ！
I told you I'm not an idiot!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
いい加減にしないと冷凍するわよ！
If you don't cut it out, I'll freeze you!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
そして粉々になって散ればいいのよ！
And then you can shatter into pieces!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot...
てれん てれん てれん...
Teren teren teren...
霊夢んとこの百万年の
The million-yen vase at Reimu's place,
壺を誰かが割っちゃった
someone went and broke it.
永遠亭のえーりんが
Eirin from Eientei,
弁償しに来ましたよ
came to pay for the damages.
知らんぷりのイタズラてね
With a feigned innocence prank,
結局賠償金額いくら？
how much is the compensation in the end?
答えは答えはゼロ円ゼロ円
The answer is, the answer is, zero yen!
なぜならなぜならそれは
Because, because that is...
そんな壺あるわけない
there's no way such a vase exists!
常識
Common sense...
超えたところに
beyond that place,
世界の真理がある
lies the truth of the world.
秘密の数字目指して
Aim for the secret number!
1！2！9！
One! Two! Nine!
ヘラヘラ ニヤけながら
While grinning foolishly,
ゲラゲラ 笑いながら
while laughing loudly.
うざー！
So annoying!
因幡ウサギ 可愛いげもないのに 新参の分際で
That Inaba rabbit isn't even cute, yet for a newcomer...
再生百万回
One million views?!
もれなく愚民なんて
Are all the commoners stupid?
どういうことなのよ どちらかって言うなら
What does this mean? If I had to say...
鯖管理もお疲れさんってとこにゃ？
Good job on the server management, I guess?
わかった！
I get it!
アタイがあまりにも天才だから 嫉妬してるんでしょ
You're just jealous because I'm such a genius!
ほんと、しょうがないわね
Honestly, it can't be helped.
せっかくだからアタイの天才の秘術を
Since I'm here, I'll teach you my genius secret arts.
ちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ！
I guess I can teach you just a little bit!
アタイとアタイとアタイとアタイと アタイとアタイとアタイと英知を
Me and me and me and me and me and me and my wisdom...
集めて集めて集めて集めて
Gather it, gather it, gather it, gather it!
束ねて束ねて束ねて束ねて 束ねても
Bundle it, bundle it, bundle it... even if you bundle it!
アタイのアタイのアタイのアタイの アタイのアタイのアタイは丈夫ね
My, my, my, my, my, my, my... I'm sturdy, aren't I?
頭に頭に頭に頭に
To the head, to the head, to the head...
適わない適わない適わない適わない 適わない
No match, no match, no match, no match!
朝飯朝飯朝飯朝飯 朝飯朝飯食べたら
Breakfast, breakfast... once I eat breakfast...
赤子の赤子の赤子の赤子の
A baby's, a baby's, a baby's...
手を捻る 手を捻る 手を捻る 手を捻る
Twist the hand, twist the hand...
アタイはアタイはアタイはアタイは
I am, I am, I am, I am...
完ぺき いわゆる
Perfect! So-called...
パーフェクト！
Perfect!
ひゃっくちょうまん ばっちり！
One hundred trillion percent spot on!
山落ち 意味など無いわ
There's no meaning to the punchline.
キャラクター 立てばいいのよ
As long as the character stands out!
元気があればなんでも
If you have energy, you can do anything!
１，２，９！
1, 2, 9!
くるくる 時計の針
Round and round, the clock hands go.
ぐるぐる 頭まわる
Spinning round, my head is spinning.
だってつぶら目玉 二つしかないのに
I mean, I only have two round eyeballs...
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかん
So three hands make no sense at all!
次々 問題出る
Problem after problem appears.
まだまだ 授業続く
The class still goes on and on.
凍る部屋の中 冷やした温度も 時間も気にせず
In this freezing room, ignoring the temperature and time...
ゆっくりしていってね！
Take it easy!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
もうバカでいいわよ！ 知らない！
Fine, I'll just be an idiot! I don't care!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
てれん てれん てれん てれん
Teren teren teren teren...
初めのダンジョンにしては手強かったなんて... なかなかやるな。
For the first dungeon, that was tough... Not bad.
よし、コインをやろう。
Alright, I'll give you a coin.
Yay! I got a coin!
だー... 外れ？
Duh... A miss?
Thank you for dancing with me!
めっちゃ楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
楽しかった。ありがとう。
It was fun. Thank you.
Thank you!
Ja, I must go. Woah, okay.
Bye bye!
うう... ああ...
Ugh... Ah...
Oh, over here already? Okay.
Ah, I see.
Well, what's next then? The rest is...
I count... one, two... two challenges left, I think,
for two coins.
待っていたぞ。
I've been waiting for you.
Bibibuu!
え？ かなた先輩？ ラプラス？
Eh? Kanata-senpai? Laplus?
What are you doing here?
これが欲しければ...
If you want this...
我々と勝負だ！
Then duel us!
My coin!
勝負だ！
It's a duel!
迫りくるゾンビを... 全部... 倒すことが...
Can you... defeat... all... the approaching zombies...
できるかな！？
I wonder!?
Oh... Well...
じゃあ、容赦は... しない！
Then, I won't... show mercy!
Run away, run away, run away you
Gonna put the pedal down
Nowhere to go, nowhere to go, nowhere to go
No road is left to run
I was born, I was born with horns
Demons couldn't shake me up
Bring it on, bring it on, bring it on
'Cause we haven't had enough
Don't give up the fight
Make it out alive
Sip this bottle, wine or blood
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you go
We're gonna make it out alive
Tonight, tonight, tonight I'm
Screaming on the inside
I was trying to hide, trying to hide, trying to hide now
Ready for this ride
Gotta face, gotta face
the unknown if it's the only way to live
I'm ready to go, ready to go, ready to go
somewhere that I've never been
Won't give up the fight
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now, whoa, whoa
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out, whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out alive
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now, whoa, whoa
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out, whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out alive
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah! Make it out! Make it out!
We're gonna make it out alive
全部倒すなんてすげーじゃん！
Defeating them all is amazing!
あ、終わった？
Oh, is it over?
勝負あり！よし！
Game over! Alright!
コインをやろう。
I'll give you a coin.
お！コイン！
Oh! A coin!
やったー！
Yay!
じゃあ、みんなありがとうね。
Well, thanks everyone.
Happy birthday.
What's happy birthday mean?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Okay.
じゃあ、さよなら！
Well, bye!
くそ！なんでできない！？
Damn! Why couldn't I do it?!
Oh... Nice landing, yeah.
Huh? Oh, it's the first stage.
Maybe this is like a... a progress check sort of thing.
Let's see... let's see where I'm at, huh?
Oh! I'm missing one more coin!
But... where could it be?
Is anyone here to give me another game or something?
Hello? Hello?
Maybe this is like the safe zone where I can like take a break and recover.
That's a good idea. You know...
I'm feeling kind of tired and all the songs have been so Biboo-ing intense.
Let's take a break. Just a nap. I'll wake up.
Hold on everyone. Just give me like 5 minutes, okay? Just 5 minutes.
Oyasumi, you know. Oyasumi.
Goodnight, you know. Goodnight.
See ya see ya.
Well come and well met, my brave little spark
How long you've wandered, burned bright as a star
Oh, I have awaited you patiently all this time
Past every fate
Now sing with me once more,
share of your life
Far greater than memory,
its loss and love words cannot hold
Boundless the tale overflows
And carries your light out to sea
Remember the rain, near and far beloved
Each drop a blessing from heavens above
And how as time flowed on those waters became one
Streams, rivers and lakes
Reaching for the horizon and far beyond
They carry onward however changed
with each brief reflection,
by setting sun
By storm's wake
Til welcomed home to gentle sea
Sinking deeper and deeper in calm embrace
Loving tides sweep in and bear you down
Should you meet a soul rising surface-ways
With your unbeatng heart, wish them well
Deep, dark, far away,
I have heard your voice, weighed your every choice
Now our hands join round the meaning you sought
I'll catch your tears,
quench your fears with joy til you near the shore
Where in time, all shall as hope be reborn,
all...
Hush love, close your eyes, and in sleep abide
As sun's distant light echoes down to dreams below
Know you will wake, on winds rise again
For this journey's end is but one step forward
to tomorrow
Wah, what a good dream.
Huuh. All right, let's check our progress then.
Umm, we're still missing one coin.
Where could it be?
Ah! Again?
What's happening?
What the beep!?
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
You... You're...
I'm you.
Me?
You mean... my last opponent is me?
Exactly. Me.
You.
Your biggest enemy.
Your biggest obstacle.
Yourself.
No...
You've done well at making it this far, Biboo.
But I don't intend to hold back.
Then, I won't either.
This stage is too important for me to give up now!
I feel like I'm losing hope
In my body and my soul
And the sky,
It looks so ominous
And as time comes to a halt
Silence starts to overflow
My cries
Are inconspicuous
Tell me God,
Are you punishing me?
Is this the price I'm paying for my past mistakes?
This
Is my redemption song
I need you more than ever right now
Can you hear me now?
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I wish that somehow, somehow
That I could save every one of us
But the truth is that I'm only one girl
Maybe if I keep believing
My dreams will come to life
Come to life
暴れる祈り
A rampage of prayer
零れる命
Crumbling life
風は
The wind is...
今も遠く
...still far away
剥がれる錆と
With peeling rust
蠢く刃
And wriggling blades
死が
In the forest...
潜む森に
...where death lurks
これが僕...
This is my...
...僕の呪い
...my curse
約束殺す痛みが
The pain that kills the promise
キミ...
Your...
...の願い
...wish
最後の夢を捨てて
Discarding the final dream
償いだけど
It is an atonement, but
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
無意味でも叫ぶ
Shouting even if it's meaningless
この汚れた世界の愛
The love of this corrupted world
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
無意味でも願う
Wishing even if it's meaningless
ただキミとの時間を
For just a moment with you
溺れた意識は
My drowning consciousness
優しいまま
Remains gentle
消えて
As it fades away
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
So now, we are...
あぁ無意味でも願う
Ah, wishing even if it's meaningless.
ただキミとの未来を
Just wishing for a future with you.
Still, we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
So now, we are...
あぁ無意味でも願う
Ah, wishing even if it's meaningless.
ただキミとの時間を
Just wishing for more time with you.
祈りが許しを得られずとも
Even if my prayers are not forgiven...
My dreams will come to life
僕は...
I am...
Haah... haah...
Impressive.
Yes! The coin!
Oh, you're still alive. Oh.
You who have defeated all the game masters shall be rewarded.
Huh? Wha- What is this?
Now, show this to everyone.
Yeah. Hey, thanks, but um...
There can only be one.
Hahahaha!
Oh, oh, I'm here. Oh, oh, oh.
Hello everyone! We have made it to the final stage!
You didn't think I collected all those coins...
...and played all those games for nothing, did you?
No, because I'm cashing it in! With all of these coins we have unlocked...
My new original song! Woohoo!
And guess what?
The video's gonna come out right after this.
Good job, everyone!
And I'm gonna perform it for you, right now!
Are you ready? Let's go out with a bang.
Rock In!
Biboo's here to play.
Yeah, uh-huh.
Woke up in the morning,
I had a funny dream.
I was a stone that had been thrown
no way back, I was all in.
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on,
and shoot my shot.
Log in, get good,
you mad? Let's cook.
Talk beep, get hit,
clean sweep.
Now you know what's up,
hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo.
Come and test your luck,
yeah we comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo.
Skipping stone in flight,
take 'em out one shot, Biboo Biboo.
Come and help me fight,
get on up let's go just me and you.
Player one and player two.
We'll see this through.
Close my eyes make a wish.
One more shot I will not miss.
Rock In!
Bububa bubububa...
Yeah... bububa bambam ba...
Yeah... bububu baba bam...
Bububu bububu bububu ba!
Level up we go onwards.
Aiming for another win.
A diamond in the rough, it's kinda tough,
you gotta keep on rollin'.
The grind goes on and on, no breaks.
Seal the cracks with a few bandaids.
I'll try over and over
and over again.
Just one more round, please?
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes
Make a wish
One more shot
I will not miss
Rock in!
Lost in this game
I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity
I see the shape
I feel the space
It's set in stone
Carve it into me
I just wanna be Biboo
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three
Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck, yeah we're comin' in clutch
Biboo's here to play
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck, yeah we're comin' in clutch
Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes
Make a wish
One more shot
I will not miss
Rock in!
Uh... Hello?
Um, I'm still here.
Ready to get teleported back to my world?
Any... anytime now.
Mom?
Pick me up!
I'm scared!
Hey!
This wasn't part of the deal!
No, wait, what are you doing?
No! No!
Hey! Listen to my song at least!
You cut my song out?! Listen to it!
Rock in! Go! Go!
Aaaah!